Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 83 in this exercise, we are going to implement
that perfect binary tree and we will create a new Java class called Perfect Binary Tree.
By the way, you can download all of these source codes for this course from the resource folder under
every lesson.
OK.
Since we are dealing with a tree, we need to create its basic building structure, which is in note,
so we start by static class, know it.
And we are dealing with a node of a tree.
We have to make a key or data structure that we are going to to store data inside it.
So it is of type input and they name it as key or you can name it as date.
I prefer key because we are working with trees and I will create a reference node that the left and
reference node for the product.
OK.
This would be like a pointer to the left and a pointer to that right.
OK, now.
In the perfect binary tree, we have said that the depth is very important in order to determine.
Determined that the structure.
Of this binary tree, if it is a perfect or not, so the depth is very important.
Before we start creating at depth, let's let me create a method that creates and you know, so both
making a new constructor for this perfect binary tree.
I will make a new method called the new note, and it's of turning Typekit note and then took into the
parameter the cake.
So when we are going to create a new node, we are going to deal with this new node method, not with
the constructor
creating node.
This is the empty constructor and we start by enclosing.
The key equals the key that it is passed.
So here we are, storing the data inside the node and enclosing the node dot right equal to no node
to the left equal to.
Not OK.
In this way, we are
creating the node initializing.
It's right and left to null and inserting inside the key.
The first parameter?
OK.
It's very simple.
And in this way, we are making everything looks perfect.
Now let's start calculating the depth.
So static and in-depth
took into the perimeter node, and we start by making into the equal to zero.
We start while looping through all the nodes in order to determine the depth of the three day plus class,
and we move the cursor cursor to node the left by one every iteration.
And then we're to tell how much it will be the depth.
Now, let's create a new method that checks for the perfect, and this is what we need.
So check if that three is perfect
binary.
Three static.
Woody Allen is perfect.
And we call, you know, it is the good and the and in level these are the perimeter of this function.
We start by calculating that start from the route which is passed and we start with the which is that
depth.
And we get also get that left how to get all of these parameters.
So let me tell you by checking the first,
if the three is empty.
So every argument of of this part of me of this function will refer for us for checking.
And it's used for checking like if the root equal equal to null, then this three is empty.
So if could
then return true?
OK.
And we have said that a single node is a perfect three.
It's very simple.
OK.
Now, if four children.
For
sure, if the dirt left equal equal to none and the route, the try equal, equal to none, then return
and.
Return the equal.
Do level plus what we are checking if d equal equal to level plus one, which is the best barometer,
if the equal two level plus one, then return is true.
Otherwise, it will return in polls.
So we have this check, we have this check and now we are going to implement another check that it assures
that the that the nodes are at the same level, no nested, no nested nodes at the left and and no and
there exist at the right nested notes or vice versa.
So it assures that and ensures that all the nodes are at the same level.
So rude don't left those equally if to none or.
If we have a route to try equal, if we to know if any of this would equal to true, then it would return
false because we don't accept any left notes.
Like at level five and level four, is that right?
Or we have at the left, the left some tree has at the left level four and at the right we have level
five.
They are not accepted.
Please go back to the previous video for the lecture in order to understand it better if you have any
problem.
Otherwise, it will return is perfect.
Recursively start testing all of these by passing through to the left.
The and level class one OK and is perfect a route to the right.
Also checking for the.
The and.
Level plus one.
OK.
It's very simple, and we are checking with the and operator recursively is perfect this, this and
this a Boolean expression and this Boolean expression, if it is true here and this is true, it will
return the true otherwise if any of this is false or both are false.
It will return false.
This is how we check for the perfect binary tree by changing this light, by using this algorithm and
comparing the Boolean expression to the left and to the right, and checking the root levels and the
depth of each of these sub trees.
Now let's make air after function that it may be
maybe confusing for you, but it's very simple.
We are just making it do
to like, break, beautify our code.
So it took it the parameter of the road and just called that perfect assert that we have created before.
But we calculate also the depth through it and we return is perfect and we passed the root.
We passed the that depth and we start from the Level Z.
OK.
This is like a a template or a general calling of our function is perfect.
Now let's create a driver class called of the main player main method.
Sorry, public static void main string are X
nodes.
It would be equal to none.
And for you, kind of create it directly here and you equal to, you know, you and your node.
You know what
we are calling the method called and, you know, because we don't have any constructor, the default
constructor, we have used it in the hammer, so we initialize the left to Node two.
We have a route through the right equal to a new Node three route to the left, to the left, equal
to new Node four and a route that.
Left the right equal to no fight, no.
Let's check if is perfect.
We passed Perfect with Capital B.
We passed through.
If it is equal, equal to true great returns, true today, we can make it like this.
It will print for a system that out the brand and three, is it perfect
finally to be otherwise, it will return.
Else, its return is not perfect by now.
But before restarting this program, let me show you what this means how what we have done.
We have the note around here.
Sorry.
On.
We have two that left to.
We have to the right three.
We have the left left this, the left and the left of it have for.
We have left.
And this left the first left, and we have the second thing is right, so left right is equal to five.
So tell me guys in the comments below if this is a perfect three or not perfect binary tree or not.
And I think, you guessed it because they are not not at the same level, so nodes are not the same
level.
It may it is not perfect.
Let's run and.
And here we go.
That tree is not a perfect binary tree.
So we have solved this exercise.
Number eight, two, three and we have created our perfect binary tree and we have created this method
that checks if it is a perfect binary tree.